

Contact Info

- +880 1716286477
- mdmarufreza@gmail.com
- www.linkedin.com/in/mdmarufreza
- House # 30/11, Shahibug
 (Commissioner Road), Savar, Dhaka-1340

Professional Qualification

Certified Supply Chain Manager (CSCM™) Institute: International Supply Chain Education Alliance (ISCEA) Passing Year: 2022

PGD in SCM Institute: BiMS Passing Year: 2021

Education Qualification

M.Sc. in Computer Science
Jahangirnagar University
2.63 out of 4.00 Year:2016

B.Sc. in EEE
United International University
2.63 out of 4.00 Year: 2013

HSC in Science Rajshahi Board

3.70 out of 5.00 Year: 2006

SSC in Science Rajshahi Board

4.50 out of 5.00 Year: 2004

Md. Maruf Reza, CSCM™

Material Requirement Planning (MRP) Expert | Procurement | SCM

Career Objective

To be an outstanding SCM professional, specially Asst./Deputy Manager or Manager level, in any renowned local or multinational organization and grow rapidly with increasing duties.

Career Summary

Around 8 years experienced supply chain management and procurement professional, with having expertise on managing good relationship with vendors, cost effective sourcing, inventory planning, team management, supply chain strategy development, procurement, product distribution and inventory management along with having lots of achievements.

Working Experience

Sr. Executive (Head of Department, MRP)(Jan 2022 - Continue)Executive (Head of Department, MRP)(Jan 2016 - Dec 2021)Officer, MRP(Jul 2014 - Dec 2015)

Nippon Paint (Bangladesh) Private Limited

Core Function:

- Conduct material requirement & inventory planning
- Analyze market & delivery systems
- Manage & maintain supplier relations
- Perform SCM process in SAP module
- Prepare RMC report of all finished goods
- Assess present & future material availability
- Develop plans for purchasing equipment along with services & supplies
- Monitor supplier performance
- Maintain inventory of all current and incoming supplies

• Keep purchase records with pricing & other information

- Maintain and update list of suppliers with all information in detail
- Maintain a very good relationship with suppliers
- Coordinate with sales, marketing and finance team

Achievements:

- Reduced the lead time of fast moving RMs by 10-15 days
- Prepared a supplier portfolio which is just a lifetime asset for the company
- Increased organizational bargaining power through introducing multiple vendors for fast moving items
- With the help of SRM, Reduced Cash to Cash Cycle by Increasing the Days payable outstanding.
- Reduced use of fractional pack size RM and minimized wastage of RM
- Simplified the purchase process for every single vendor
- Set benchmark of SCM efficiency and increased productivity & profitability
- Got Appreciation Award for being a part of standardization of Operational Planning Report (ZSDR1)
- Implemented the modern SCM techniques to improve the Financial KPIs
- Improved overall supply chain performance

Skills

- Communication
- Team Player
- Decision Making
- Presentation
- Time Management
- Organization
- Negotiation

Computer

- MS Word
- MS Excel
- PowerPoint
- SAP

Language

- Bengali: Proficient
- English: Good Working Knowledge

Personal Info

Father: Md. Rezaul Mustafa

Mother: Arzu Monoara

Birth: 10th July, 1989

Marital Status: Married

Nationality: Bangladeshi

NID: 4601988100

Md. Maruf Reza, CSCM™

Material Requirement Planning (MRP) Expert | Procurement | SCM

Previous Working Experience

Site Engineer , Telecom (Aug 2013 – Jul 2014)

Express System Ltd.

Junior System Engineer, CITS (Feb 2013 – Aug 2013)

United International University

Expertise

- Inventory Management
- Process Improvement
- Business Intelligent
- Demand Planning
- Strategic Sourcing
- Logistics Management

Training & Course

Procurement Policy by Creative Professional Development Associate
 Duration: 01 Day
 Year: 2021

• Communication Skill by HR Perception

Duration: 01 Day Year: 2021

Leadership Skill by HR Perception

Duration: 01 Day Year: 2021

Business Intelligent by Nippon Paint (Bangladesh) Private Limited
 Duration: 02 Days
 Year: 2015

CCNA Local Certified by United International University

Duration: 08 Months Year: 2012

Reference

Mohammad Mamun Elahi Md. Alamgir Hossain

Assistant Professor, CSE SAVP & Head of Branch United International University Jamuna Bank Limited

+8801914001570 +8801716067526

mmelahi@cse.uiu.ac.bd kbdalamgir@yahoo.com